ADAM SPRIGGS

(613) 408-5990



adam.spriggs7@gmail.com



https://www.linkedin.com/in/adam-spriggs-aa43a510b



http://adamspriggs.me

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE

4 TH YEAR STUDENT

Honours, concentration in Computer and Internet Security Carleton University (4th year) 2017-2021

SKILLS

Java
JavaScript
C / C++
Python
Microsoft Office
Linux / Windows
Project design and architecture
Qt Creator
PKI services
AD CS
DNS
Software Engineering Design
Hack the Box (HTB)

CERTIFICATIONS

CompTIA Network+

National Lifeguard
Lifesaving Instructor
Standard First Aid Instructor
Standard First Aid Examiner
National Lifeguard Instructor
Bronze Medallion / Cross Examiner
National Lifeguard Examiner
Advanced Instructor

PERSONAL PROFILE

Currently going through Carleton University's Bachelor of Computer Science degree, I have a strong interest in artificial intelligence, network and computer security and Hack the Box challenges. This interest has prompted me to do personal research into these topics and their implementation together. I have a strong determination, adaptability, and drive allowing me to do my personal projects, complete my degree with honours and finish with a minor in Business.

EXPERIENCE

JUNIOR IT SECURITY ANALYST, NETWORK DEVICE AUTHENTICATION

Shared Services Canada, Government of Canada / Ottawa, CA / June 2019 - Present

Working with my team at Shared Services Canada, I attained valuable skills in leadership, working in a group and time management. I also learned the importance of security for government and public. As an IT security analyst, my key contributions were:

- Demonstrated skills with active directory certificate services.
- Supported operations team.
- Understanding up PKI services and certificates.
- Part of team responsible for transitioning most departments from their own PKI systems to Shared Services Canada's and Communications Security Establishment standards and hardware / servers.
- Created a production style PKI system in a personal sandbox for testing purposes.
- Understand the importance of operating system hardening and auditing

LIFEGAURD, INSTRUCTOR, EXAMINER

City of Ottawa / 2015 – Present

As a lifeguard with the City of Ottawa, I see and are responsible for several hundred lives as they swim in the wave pool that I work at. Should something occur, my duty as a lifeguard is to prevent further injury and dedicate help to whomever may need it. As an instructor and examiner, my job is to train future lifeguards and examine whether they are fit or not to be given the National Lifeguard distinction.

- With these positions, I hold a great deal of responsibility to patrons and legal obligations to uphold.
- Travel across Ottawa giving the National Lifeguard distinction.
- Leading life or death situations, communicating clearly.
- Acquired thorough interpersonal skills with my colleagues and the general public
- Complaint resolution